Alan Houston

Full Stack Web Developer

3900 Tamil St. Austin, TX 78749 512.993.6800 AlanHouston.dev AlanHouston5000@gmail.com

Gaining experience from a diverse background, I pride myself on my communication skills, multitasking, and organizational proficiency. I work well with my peers and enjoy solving complex business problems collaboratively. I love learning and enjoy keeping myself and my peers focused, motivated, and in good spirits!

WORK EXPERIENCE

Vybe Software *Austin, TX*

WEB DEVELOPER. JUNE 2019 - PRESENT

- Ongoing maintenance, customer support, QA for Leia: Website Builder: heyleia.com & Leia for Real Estate: rev.heyleia.com
- Design and create 250+ front end section templates for current version of Leia: Website Builder; strict, editor specific HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript, UX/UI
- JS functionality, API calls to multiple Realtor.com endpoints on RapidAPI for search function and results for Leia for Real Estate
- Currently creating API's & building Wordpress plugins and themes to integrate Leia products into the platform
- Optimize subscribing clients' on-page SEO
- Assume ancillary tasks due to small-scale startup, four person team

Grassroots Realty Austin, TX

REALTOR®, APRIL 2017 - PRESENT

DEN Property Group Austin, TX

REALTOR®, AUGUST 2013 - APRIL 2017

- Primary focus: Customer service with constant communication
- Generate leads & maintain client relationships
- High dollar contract management
- Property management

Habitat Camping Rentals Austin, TX

OWNER/OPERATOR, MAY 2014 - PRESENT

- Project management during large multiple night festivals, 20-100 customers, crew of 2-6
- Inventory management: purchasing, maintaining, and storing 100's of inventory items
- B2B marketing to local festivals and venue owners
- End of fiscal year tax preparation

Austin Coding Academy Austin, TX

ADMISSIONS ADVISOR, MAY 2019 - JUNE 2019

- Communicate via phone/email with prospective students, guiding them through the decision to level up their career into the tech industry
- Admissions process: initial interview, admissions assignment, followup calls, acceptance, and onboarding

TUTOR. MAY 2019 - JUNE 2019

- Provide individual and small group tutoring to students
- Assist students in improving academic achievement by meeting with them on a regular basis to clarify learning objectives

Mohawk Austin. TX

VENUE MANAGER, DECEMBER 2008 - JULY 2015

- Manage flow of 1000+ customers, 35+ shift employees: bar, production, floor, & security
- Fast-paced, constantly changing environment, continually adapting
- High responsibility: cash & safe balances, key holding: first to arrive, last to leave, staff scheduling
- Face of company: interface with day-of promoters, police department, fire marshall, health enforcement, TABC, etc

SKILLS

JavaScript • PHP • Node.js • Express.js • React • MySQL • MariaDB • MongoDB • Mongoose WordPress • jQuery • HTML • CSS • Bootstrap • RESTful API • Git/GitHub • Linux • Webpack Websocket • Angular Conversational Spanish

EDUCATION

Austin Coding Academy - Full Stack Web Developer Program - AUGUST 2018 - MAY 2019

Texas State University - BBA, Finance AUGUST 2000 - DECEMBER 2004